# SPENCER J. VIGIL

600 Barwood Park Austin, TX 78753 · (682) 365-1637 · spencervigil27@gmail.com

Experienced economic and analytical consultant with a demonstrated history of working in the tech industry. Skilled in statistical modeling, analytic skills, JavaScript and jQuery. Strong business development professional with a Master of Science (MS) focused in Economic Research from University of North Texas and graduate of University of Texas Full Stack Web Development Program.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## WEB.com - Austin, Texas: Data Specialist

May 2017 - May 2018

- Enable my teams with relevant strategic and operational recommendations to increase production.
- Turn data-driven observations into actionable processes from the macro to the micro level.
- Learned and understood sales process from initial call to point of sale to improve performance.

### Entrepreneurial and Independent Consultant - Austin, Texas

May 2015 – Apr. 2017

- Created solutions as an independent contractor for various clients in real estate and development.
- Managed own time and provided quick turnaround results when needed.
- Created theoretical model for predicting financial literacy.
- Made strategic management decisions including app content, funds allocation and personnel.

## Buxton - Fort Worth, Texas: Senior Predictive Analyst

Jan. 2014 - Jun. 2015

- Modelled consumer and patient behavior that improved performance of existing and future sites.
- Provided analytic expertise during client delivery that resulted in better understanding of results.
- Improved processes and quality control as a tenured analyst.
- Identified trends in client data to paint a picture of why certain sites were successful.

#### Buxton - Fort Worth, Texas: Research Analyst

Aug. 2011 - Dec. 2013

- Formulated mathematical models for clients including retail, restaurant, grocery, and healthcare.
- Provided guick turnaround results for ad hoc client reguests.
- Designed and improved client-facing deliverables and presentations.

**Lonesome Dove Restaurant**, Austin, Texas: *Server* **Reata Restaurant**, Fort Worth, Texas: *Server* 

Jun. 2015 – Nov. 2016

Aug. 2005 - Aug. 2014

## **SKILLS**

- Analytics: Statistics, Regression Analysis, Theoretical Model Building, Machine Learning, A/B testing
- Proficient Computer Skills: Alteryx, ESRI Business Analyst, Microsoft Office, PL SQL, SAS, Tableau
- Working Knowledge Computer Skills: Python, R, Salesforce, STATA, Visual Basic

### **EDUCATION**

## University of North Texas, Denton, Texas

Master of Science of Economic Research, December 2013

GPA: 3.5

Relevant Courses: Applied Econometrics, Time Series Forecasting, Adv. Econometrics, Adv. Macro/Micro Economics Independent Study: Fit a panel data model studying the fixed effects of how broadband technology affects GDP across 50 nations and 7 years. Found that wireless broadband technology has a positive influence on GDP. This is true as an independent input once labor and capital are accounted for and as a technology factor modifying capital.

Bachelor of Business Administration in Economics (Minor in Spanish), May 2011

GPA: 3.5

Honors: President's List, Dean's List

Activities: Integrated Business Case Competition, Fourth Place Study Abroad: AIP Language School, Valencia, Spain (Summer 2007)

Relevant Courses: Empirical Linear Modeling, Excel Development Workshop, Differential Equations, Multivariable

Calculus, Linear Algebra & Vector Geometry